<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-29T00:19:58-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dr. Rick Wysocki</title><entry><title type="html">Sonic Sleuth 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/21/sonic-sleuth-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sonic Sleuth 4" /><published>2018-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/21/sonic-sleuth-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/21/sonic-sleuth-4.html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s this week’s “sonic sleuth” post, where I list ten songs I can’t stop playing, and brief descriptions of why. Feel free to follow if you want to hear some cool songs and read some nerdy thoughts about music. I promise I’ll try to deliver some every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;say-yes-by-elliott-smith&quot;&gt;Say Yes by Elliott Smith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always loved Elliott Smith. There’s something about the interaction of the vocal melody and the guitar part that is just so incredible on this song. And, because it’s Elliott Smith, the lyrics are amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/1KrF0WEsMkLB3Nvczyb20a?si=SR3ydJn9QlyXOjjSa5TVBQ&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-by-noname&quot;&gt;Self by Noname&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just started listening to this album, and it is excellent. Gives me some serious Erykah Badu vibes (among others) in a way that I’m not sure anything else has. It’s dope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2wUnFLr2k5491Pv4cUYd83?si=VX2LJp2ATzeUfYdx6u_gPQ&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fuck-gravity-by-virtual-riot&quot;&gt;Fuck Gravity by Virtual Riot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dude  can produce electronic music. For. Real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/7CU2gGLgHim3t2zx4S0BEV?si=NJHyBY9XSA-WzNg75fdE0g&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;spit-on-a-stranger-by-pavement&quot;&gt;Spit on a Stranger by Pavement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched the music episode of that Netflix series “The Nineties” and it didn’t mention Pavement once. That show is cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/05l9N6SnERhSdH8XQR5TjK?si=pyl8LL5kSW2CKdLO7ecLPA&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nancy-drew-by-fat-creeps&quot;&gt;Nancy Drew by Fat Creeps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So surfy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3z5hddVJjNRypALWKaYnTq?si=62MM60H_TEiqf9iytb1m_g&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern-girl-by-sleater-kinney&quot;&gt;Modern Girl by Sleater Kinney&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song might have the best buildup to a drum part of all time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2TV1CEAFvQiiLhqxUOCQnC?si=mP_cmt2fQr2309prQb4o-A&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;they-reminisce-over-you-by-pete-rock-and-cl-smooth&quot;&gt;They Reminisce Over You by Pete Rock and C.L. Smooth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That. Sample.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2Mb3zpobD0CvJGWv6NpsPy?si=UvWWSShNQEqVViGRX-NdQw&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kiss-kiss-bang-bang-by-high-contrast&quot;&gt;Kiss Kiss Bang Bang by High Contrast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty dope D&amp;amp;B song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/1ywMblwTVaMexGnwsA1J7k?si=bwtQ-0OLTS2v1lCCXqOh8Q&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;celebrate-by-destra&quot;&gt;Celebrate by Destra&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay. I have no idea how I came upon Destra, but I love it. They are so, so, so, so, good. So. Good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MHnAItGNfxI&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;above-the-clouds-by-gang-starr-and-inspectah-deck&quot;&gt;Above the Clouds by Gang Starr and Inspectah Deck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read this blog at all you already know how I feel about Gang Starr. This song is yet more proof that they are the greatest of all time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/7Guni9Kv4cxajoglZLzfuN?si=1X_M677wTzeG8IrGSx6Z4A&quot;&gt;Song Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">Here’s this week’s “sonic sleuth” post, where I list ten songs I can’t stop playing, and brief descriptions of why. Feel free to follow if you want to hear some cool songs and read some nerdy thoughts about music. I promise I’ll try to deliver some every week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Information</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/12/on-information.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Information" /><published>2018-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/12/on-information</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/12/on-information.html">&lt;p&gt;One might imagine that, at some point in the past, the acquisition of “information” was seen as an additive benefit to an individual’s ability to move through life. This ability—again, in this imagined past—was somehow linked with another phenomena thought of as “knowledge”—the more information one accumulated, the more knowledge in their store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This imagined past is not, of course, an objectively and historically existing entity. History itself is far too fractured and non-linear, and the idea that concepts like “information” and “knowledge” could be discussed in any easy way would be rebuked by a scholar familiar with the academic literature in virtually any field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, the impulse to consider all information as an added benefit to human life remains. And it’s accelerated with the advent of digital technologies. Here’s an (admittedly somewhat silly) example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a trailer for Revolt’s recent hip-hop “hot takes” show &lt;em&gt;State of the Culture&lt;/em&gt;, former rapper-turned-media personality Joe Budden adopts a presidential ethos to address a crowd of paid extras. “Decoding the culture” being the theme of the show (the “culture” referring to hip-hop culture), Budden continuously refers to the relationships between information and culture, stating bombastically at one point that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this digital age there is an endless need for information. It is more important now than ever before. With more information, comes more understanding, more acceptance, more unification. Information is the key to unlocking our differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use this as an example not because I find the show particularly important to larger conceptions of information, but because it is so clearly a commercialization of the &lt;em&gt;very idea&lt;/em&gt; of information, which is, in fact, the product Budden sells. I also do not single out this show as an exceptional example in any sense except the obviousness of its strategy. Budden exists in a country plagued by structural racism and disenfranchisement. The fact that he has managed to thrive and develop a show for a black-owned television network makes me more forgiving than when I see—oh, let’s take a quick look… Oh here’s a great headline from &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;: “An Amy Winehouse Hologram is Going on Tour In 2019 and Some Fans Aren’t Happy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of “information” isn’t going to make you more informed. At best, and this is a stretch, reading the &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt; might distract you from your day to day nuisances and make you the target of advertisements. I happen to think the latter one is actually quite dangerous, but you might be in the market for a new pair of sneakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my point. Information does not always mean the same thing. It &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; mean knowledge. It can also mean the data about you and me constantly being distributed and traded across digital networks. In cognitively-dangerous conspiracy circles, information can mean the infinitesimally small data points that &lt;em&gt;seemingly&lt;/em&gt; contradict  established scientific consensus. (Of course, it nearly never does, at least in the way it’s purported to by conspiracy theorists.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We absolutely &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; rid ourselves of the notion that information, and access to information, is necessarily a benefit to our collective life on this planet. And we must be compassionate but firm on this point. The “information” received on &lt;em&gt;Breitbart&lt;/em&gt; about climate change is not true, and I have yet to see a single article from Breitbart that would pass my introductory course on writing and research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet has flattened the status of all information, because it all seems to exist side-by-side. With the scandals emerging nearly constantly regarding the circulation our data, we are seeing cracks in this dangerous ideology. Still, public citizens need to work to re-instill the concept of &lt;em&gt;credible&lt;/em&gt; information. And we need to do so not just with our dollars but with our eyes, which have themselves been commodified as “streams” and “clicks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In lieu of a prescriptive remedy, here is one from Franco “Bifo” Berardi:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[T]he task of the general intellect is precisely this: to escape from paranoia, to create zones of human resistance, to experiment with autonomous forms of production based on high-tech/low-energy models, to interpellate the people with a language that is more therapeutic than political. (The Soul at Work)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fostering a nuanced approach that asks whether particular information/information sources are beneficial to collective life is this first step toward the crucial project described by Berardi.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">One might imagine that, at some point in the past, the acquisition of “information” was seen as an additive benefit to an individual’s ability to move through life. This ability—again, in this imagined past—was somehow linked with another phenomena thought of as “knowledge”—the more information one accumulated, the more knowledge in their store.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sonic Sleuth 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/07/sonic-sleuth-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sonic Sleuth 3" /><published>2018-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/07/sonic-sleuth-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/07/sonic-sleuth-3.html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s this week’s “sonic sleuth” post, where I list ten songs I can’t stop playing, and brief descriptions of why. Feel free to follow if you want to hear some cool songs and read some nerdy thoughts about music. I promise I’ll try to deliver some every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dopamine-by-franc-moody&quot;&gt;Dopamine by Franc Moody&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bass line is so good. So, so good. Reminds me of Teddy Prendergass and also the Ohio Players for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2MTSo2SGQ0oVKgPu99x3Df?si=ZP9QzWBkQce1_tj4xZaKiA&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shouldnt-have-done-that-by-two-another&quot;&gt;Shouldn’t Have Done That by Two Another&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song sounds like what I always wished Sam Smith sounded like. That’s not to take anything away from either artist (I’m really digging this band and have always liked Sam Smith, too), but I can’t get over the mix between the crooning vocals and the ethereal synthesizers here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5AU3s8f01DFRzdlevVpJkB?si=Do851Ud6SHSBmk6qbAQnjg&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;judy-french-by-white-reaper&quot;&gt;Judy French by White Reaper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever lived in Louisville you can’t not love White Reaper. This band rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/7f4MQxuZWk6iMI4KygEC7P?si=FLvtteLMTEW4SvNG2UNTAA&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dripping-by-blonde-redhead&quot;&gt;Dripping by Blonde Redhead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to see Blonde Redhead at a festival at some point (it was either Coachella or Austin City Limits) and it was fantastic. This band is incredible and deserves more props than it gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/19haPvVWVxPqlUSQmQYgNd?si=iG57FvDVQIWkjE6QjUYTUw&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-would-i-want-sky-by-animal-collective&quot;&gt;What Would I Want? Sky by Animal Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay I know everyone and their dog’s dad probably knows this song but I’ve been listening to it again lately. It’s so dope that the Grateful Dead let Animal Collective sample “Unbroken Chain”–the first time the Dead had ever cleared a sample.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3RQDauUKDwVNsg2IVypyMo?si=KBnL1DaxSGe_joYU-zctUg&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-time-high-remix-of-an-eluardian-instance-by-of-montreal-by-recontructionist&quot;&gt;First Time High (Remix of An Eluardian Instance by Of Montreal) by Recontructionist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m aware that this is a very complicated title. To be clear, it’s a remix of an Of Montreal song by an artist called Reconstructionist. Not totally sure where I came across this, but I dig it, and am a forever-fan of Of Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3uD7fHUG9OYARp958ZIlFr?si=UFSsxrJARGmwdcvIsx5ybA&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;god-by-kendrick-lamar&quot;&gt;GOD. by Kendrick Lamar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not trying to argue with anyone about this, but Kendrick is my personal favorite rapper. DAMN was such an incredible album (LOVE. is one of my all-time favorite songs). GOD. doesn’t seem to get talked about as much as it should, though. So, here, listen to it and think about how great it is. If you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5p3NP9mQblDsVJLdfNZJ3I?si=Bg1p-VXeQX2nVOetArUqxw&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hustle-formation-by-the-go-team&quot;&gt;Hustle Formation by The GO! Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seidenfaden’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/6O61pROWlBVw4T6RszE4C4?si=Xqt4iDp2QJe2o7HHmOfvVA&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rock-n-roll-star-by-kero-kero-bonito&quot;&gt;Rock n Roll Star by Kero Kero Bonito&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know what my musical taste is, this is a pretty good distillation of it. Occasionally glitchy electronic drums, 80s vibes, movement through a couple different moods, vocal harmonies–this song has it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5TlobeBLLovqgVtwq4zTCp?si=8kRu5FavQLK3W4MSQaaYvA&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shock-doctrine-by-sts9&quot;&gt;Shock Doctrine by STS9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song brings me back to high school so hard. I love it. (As a political aside, also read Naomi Klein’s book that this song is named after: &lt;em&gt;Shock Doctrine: The Rise of Disaster Capitalism.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/6FxvBPEkoxedM7IrQdqeVZ?si=pqPoHKjCSm-CugdeC8k5QA&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">Here’s this week’s “sonic sleuth” post, where I list ten songs I can’t stop playing, and brief descriptions of why. Feel free to follow if you want to hear some cool songs and read some nerdy thoughts about music. I promise I’ll try to deliver some every week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Loss</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/05/loss.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Loss" /><published>2018-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/05/loss</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/05/loss.html">&lt;p&gt;Today, to channel some of my own anger at the present state of politics, I read some of Wendy Brown’s book &lt;em&gt;Undoing the Demos: Neoliberalism’s Stealth Revolution.&lt;/em&gt; The book, which came out in 2015, was prescient in analyzing trends in political, economic, and social life, especially the neoliberal slide towards “info-tainment” in so-called political discourse. Since I can’t articulate my own thoughts today, here are some of hers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This persistence of politics amid the destruction of public life and especially educated public life, combined with the marketization of the political sphere, is part of what makes contemporary politics peculiarly unappealing and toxic–full of ranting and posturing, emptied of intellectual seriousness, pandering to an uneducated and manipulable electorate and a celebrity-scandal-hungry corporate media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure Brown could have foreseen how much further this trend would go. And it is absolutely devastating that it has gone as far as it has.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">Today, to channel some of my own anger at the present state of politics, I read some of Wendy Brown’s book Undoing the Demos: Neoliberalism’s Stealth Revolution. The book, which came out in 2015, was prescient in analyzing trends in political, economic, and social life, especially the neoliberal slide towards “info-tainment” in so-called political discourse. Since I can’t articulate my own thoughts today, here are some of hers:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Music</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/05/new-music.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Music" /><published>2018-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/05/new-music</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/10/05/new-music.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey, y’all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put a new song up on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/rlw1234&quot;&gt;soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; last night. I’ve been focusing a lot on the dissertation/job market (obviously) and some web design projects in my free time, so my music has been taking a little bit of a back seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know, music was one of my first loves (far earlier than academia, actually), and I produce electronic music as a hobby. I’ve been forever working on an EP that I’ll put out someday. But not today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, last night I just convinced myself to compose something short that sounded nice and avoided falling into the familiar tracks of “overthinking it.” So, here it is–if you like it, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/510659859&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">Hey, y’all!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sonic Sleuth 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/09/29/sonic-sleuth-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sonic Sleuth 2" /><published>2018-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/09/29/sonic-sleuth-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/09/29/sonic-sleuth-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Once a week, I post a list of ten songs I can’t stop playing, and brief descriptions of why. Er, the goal is once a week. Since I’ve fallen off posting (and lost a few posts in the series when moving my blog), I’ve decided to rebrand this series as “Sonic Sleuth” and try to get back into the weekly posts. So, in any case, feel free to follow if you want to hear some cool songs and read some nerdy thoughts about music. I promise I’ll try to deliver some every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lose-your-love-by-joe-goddard&quot;&gt;Lose Your Love by Joe Goddard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that this song doesn’t bang as hard as it could is, to me, what makes it such a banger. A true enigma. I’ve been listening to Joe Goddard’s stuff a ton lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2VKO3Jo5Zgi4lKkazhtJlI?si=VKl707LuTI-ncmoR5FR80w&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lovers-carving-by-bibio&quot;&gt;lovers’ carving by Bibio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I’ve gotten this into a guitar song, even though I grew up playing guitar pretty seriously. There’s just something about this song I really dig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3JeT6Xcv6MlEHHylk8SKQ1?si=Ff6IjTr6Q1q1fzJLj3cONg&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beyond-my-eyes-by-bibio&quot;&gt;Beyond My Eyes by Bibio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to avoid doubling up artists on these lists, but it is too strange that this song is by the same musician as the previous one. I had to include it. While they’re both great, this song is much more in my usual style. It’s got great synths and lots of development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2jAu8NfpemA0BMYRP0WGbx?si=lVzYEhgUQSaEIsRMEjPuGQ&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bamboo-by-elder-island&quot;&gt;Bamboo by Elder Island&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THIS. SONG. IS. REALLY. REALLY. REALLY. REALLY. GOOD. For real, this is one of the cooler songs I’ve heard in a while. It’s got a weird time signature that doesn’t come across as weird, a mallet sound that reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Y0lLwLxVX8&quot;&gt;Oingo Boing’s&lt;/a&gt; “Just Another Day,” and great vocals. It’s slow, dance-y, soft, and in your face at different times. Just a really great song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2MzQd7zPsbN73mjr90AkL0?si=cpFV-mjSTyqVMVGq2XU5zA&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alone-together-by-leisure&quot;&gt;Alone Together by LEISURE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a pretty straightforward pop-song but its just works really well. I hear some Steely Dan vibes going on in the chorus. If you don’t know me, that means I’m in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/7Cmv3ut6lDHba6m1OxZXZe?si=yZDpVVYmSLS-NzX_3Q8Xpg&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hunnybee-by-unknown-mortal-orchestra&quot;&gt;Hunnybee by Unknown Mortal Orchestra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2chill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3DPFmwFtV5ElQaTniLOdgk?si=dSpKebocSEyjNXuaq57HfQ&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-that-we-found-love-by-heavy-d--the-boyz&quot;&gt;Now That We Found Love by Heavy D &amp;amp; The Boyz&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contain multitudes and if you don’t like Heavy D you’re messing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/1KONmY3enP3r3nIPQidWAy?si=uLSf35wVRL6gvp_4pkWpUg&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cutlass-cruiser-by-tops&quot;&gt;Cutlass Cruiser by TOPS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song is cool as hell. Reminds me both of great 80s pop and also the Ariel Pink-ish vibes of the years I was living in California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/6rnMwp1TDEw8wwbX7S9Ot9?si=p-NITGQjS0CzNeZvXtqlaw&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-camera-by-yumi-zouma&quot;&gt;In Camera by Yumi Zouma&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can’t get enough of those 80s bass/guitar countermelodies. And the chorus just feels so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/4vcyK8QHE6WsqiSnaBOtOS?si=3wVasjDzSEq-kSdLHEj_Rg&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kod-by-j-cole&quot;&gt;KOD by J. Cole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been rocking this a ton lately. No idea why (beside it being dope).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/7yotKA30dwTKNEGomV9ZsI?si=b262bvE-THK0afwSdFbI2w&quot;&gt;Spotify Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">Once a week, I post a list of ten songs I can’t stop playing, and brief descriptions of why. Er, the goal is once a week. Since I’ve fallen off posting (and lost a few posts in the series when moving my blog), I’ve decided to rebrand this series as “Sonic Sleuth” and try to get back into the weekly posts. So, in any case, feel free to follow if you want to hear some cool songs and read some nerdy thoughts about music. I promise I’ll try to deliver some every week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dogfood</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/09/26/dogfood.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dogfood" /><published>2018-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/09/26/dogfood</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/09/26/dogfood.html">&lt;p&gt;This past week, I finally pulled the plug and deleted my Facebook account. Or, rather, I scheduled my Facebook to be deleted in two weeks since, apparently, the company doesn’t allow users to delete accounts without giving itself a grace period. A lot of friends have pointed out real things I might miss by not being on the platform, but I feel so much lighter without the Facebook echo chamber in my head. I don’t judge people who stay on the platform–I’m not an evangelist–but it just wasn’t working for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading a bit about the IndieWeb movement, and am becoming increasingly interested in the possibility of a more decentralized model for distributing web content. This is moving me toward two related projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To increasingly post content here, on my personal site, and only then distribute it to other platforms. I’ve also set up a &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/rickwysocki&quot;&gt;micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; for similar purposes related to Twitter. (I do use my &lt;a href=&quot;www.twitter.com&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for a number of professional reasons, so I’ll continue to post there as well.) Additionally, I’m going to set up comments with Staticman on this site to add more interactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To make a greater effort to create or at least have some hand in designing digital tools for my own work work. To this end, I’ve begun developing a (very small scale) Jekyll template for creating and disseminating oral history archives (called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rickwysocki/oryll-hystory&quot;&gt;Oryll Hystory&lt;/a&gt;). With my scholarly background in both new media and archival theory, I’m hoping to use this as a prototype for thinking through questions regarding digital archives, circulation, and public humanities work. If that doesn’t work out, it will at least be practice for a bigger and better project. Feel free to follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rickwysocki/oryll-hystory&quot;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt; for the project if you’re interested. But don’t judge me–I’m at the early stages of the project and its currently &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; basic (and doesn’t look particularly good yet either).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s where I’m at. Hopefully I’ll be able to stick to this. Maybe if we all take back our content, we’ll find better ways of sharing it with each other. Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">This past week, I finally pulled the plug and deleted my Facebook account. Or, rather, I scheduled my Facebook to be deleted in two weeks since, apparently, the company doesn’t allow users to delete accounts without giving itself a grace period. A lot of friends have pointed out real things I might miss by not being on the platform, but I feel so much lighter without the Facebook echo chamber in my head. I don’t judge people who stay on the platform–I’m not an evangelist–but it just wasn’t working for me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/09/18/some-updates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some Updates" /><published>2018-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/09/18/some-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/09/18/some-updates.html">&lt;p&gt;A lot’s been going on recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should say, first, that I’ve added some new information to my website. I’ve updated my &lt;a href=&quot;https://rickwysocki.com/research/&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rickwysocki.com/teaching/&quot;&gt;teaching&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://rickwysocki.com/curriculum-vitae/&quot;&gt;CV&lt;/a&gt; pages with revised documents, and have added some pages to begin showcasing some of my &lt;a href=&quot;https://rickwysocki.com/portfolio/&quot;&gt;creative work&lt;/a&gt;. There’s scant content there now, but I’ll add pages for my electronic music, design work, and very amateur photography over the next couple of weeks. A lot of this will change, but I’m slowly trying to take control of my digital self, a decision that’s leading me to delete my Facebook at the end end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s the more important &lt;i&gt;a lots&lt;/i&gt; that have been going on recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve completed four chapters of my dissertation. It feels unreal, and I’m surprisingly happy with what I’ve produced so far. I’m getting to spend a lot more time with my partner, her dog (my other dog), and my cat, who are all now sharing the same space with us. It’s wonderful. I’m also on the on ramp the academic job market. It’s going to be a long but rewarding year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">A lot’s been going on recently.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Songs I Love, Volume 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/05/05/songs-I-love-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Songs I Love, Volume 1" /><published>2018-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/05/05/songs-I-love-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/05/05/songs-I-love-1.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first of a new series of blog posts I’m starting. It’s called “Songs I Love” and, obviously, it’s about music I love that I’ve been listening to lately. Each Sunday, I’ll post ten songs I’ve been listening to lately and give one-ish sentence descriptions explaining why I love them. If you want to follow along at home, I’ll post links to the individual songs on Spotify and Youtube, when possible, as well as a full playlist at the bottom of the post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prince-rama-never-forever&quot;&gt;Prince Rama: Never Forever&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this song because it’s weird as hell, and because they were super dope when I saw them opening for Dan Deacon. &lt;em&gt;[This one isn’t on Spotify, so here’s a Youtube link to their also weird as hell music video.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BAu9WWe4Sfs&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pavement-transport-is-arranged&quot;&gt;Pavement: Transport is Arranged&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my top five running songs–the dynamics between the soft and heavy parts are so interesting and well-produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/5DnkE7FBXO3deUSTE3rV30&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;muscles-the-lake&quot;&gt;Muscles: The Lake&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That chorus is just too tight. Whenever I listen to it I picture a big dance routine in my head for some reason. If you like synthesizers, this whole album is worth a listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/2yYtodUNySTH1O5hVyD4oO&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lcd-soundsystem-someone-great&quot;&gt;LCD Soundsystem: Someone Great&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend and I couldn’t agree whether this was a happy or a sad song (I say sad). Regardless, it’s super-beautiful and is probably my favorite LCD Soundsystem track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/2VGDntFPvgvqSiUf9ITEfW&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;daft-punk-something-about-us&quot;&gt;Daft Punk: Something About Us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So smooth–undervalued in Daft Punk’s discography in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/1NeLwFETswx8Fzxl2AFl91&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thundercat-lava-lamp&quot;&gt;Thundercat: Lava Lamp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even smoother–Thundercat is probably my favorite artist of 2018, and also helped make To Pimp a Butterfly so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/1FgDXkEcfp49bSrNSM8jzS&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fanny-j-dis-le-moi&quot;&gt;Fanny J: Dis-le-moi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right. Zouk music rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/4ImXD6ZpFot6C2gK5DOwys&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;yelletepr-ce-jeu-tepr-remix&quot;&gt;Yelle/Tepr: Ce Jeu (Tepr Remix)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this song because it reminds me of driving around with my friends in Dallas growing up and looking for something to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/0GW4OxkqXa32DBmscR6wbV&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;erykah-badu-four-leaf-clover&quot;&gt;Erykah Badu: Four Leaf Clover&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s Erykah Badu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/66q8IX1czlTF7BUYZ7CNts&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oneohtrix-point-never-sticky-drama&quot;&gt;Oneohtrix Point Never: Sticky Drama&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this song because it’s so uncomfortable and digital-grimy but simultaneously so melodic. The production is so incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/01e4KUhkyzTJC2FjBkEmsn&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;entire-playlist-minus-prince-rama&quot;&gt;Entire Playlist (Minus Prince Rama)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/rlwysockijr/playlist/0IXCXzNzDNvO3zLFCjzQAu&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">This is the first of a new series of blog posts I’m starting. It’s called “Songs I Love” and, obviously, it’s about music I love that I’ve been listening to lately. Each Sunday, I’ll post ten songs I’ve been listening to lately and give one-ish sentence descriptions explaining why I love them. If you want to follow along at home, I’ll post links to the individual songs on Spotify and Youtube, when possible, as well as a full playlist at the bottom of the post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Personal Historical Marker</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/05/01/personal-historical-marker.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Personal Historical Marker" /><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/05/01/personal-historical-marker</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-design%20life/2018/05/01/personal-historical-marker.html">&lt;p&gt;I have a stack of former students’ reflection papers on my desk in front of me. As I’m drafting this blog post, I’m picking one up when I’m not sure what to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tell my students that all writers struggle to produce words, and that picking up other writers’ texts can help break through what often feels like a barrier between yourself and the page. (Or, more likely, the screen.) It makes me glad to use &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; writing for this task now, since so many of them entered my introductory college composition course with devalued ideas about their capabilities and possibilities as writers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, I submitted the grades for my two sections of Business Writing this semester. The next day, I cleaned out my office desk. I am privileged to have been granted a dissertation fellowship for my final year at my university, during which I’ll be able to focus entirely on my research and the job-market-marathon beginning in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels odd knowing that I’ll likely never teach another course at the University of Louisville. Apart from a largely disastrous preceptorial course I organized in my undergraduate Honors program (a story for another time), I learned everything I know about teaching here. My first courses were fall and spring of 2014-15, one a section of introductory college composition and the other a more research-focused composition course. Since then, I’ve taught multiple sections of business writing, scientific and technical writing, and an American literature survey. I learned so much in simply teaching each course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is more of a historical marker for me than a narrative or argument, I suppose. I just feel so lucky to have worked with my students, and to know that while I’ll be out of the classroom for a year, a future of teaching awaits me on the other side of this dissertation. Speaking of which…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-design life" /><summary type="html">I have a stack of former students’ reflection papers on my desk in front of me. As I’m drafting this blog post, I’m picking one up when I’m not sure what to write.</summary></entry></feed>