<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-08T21:38:55-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dr. Rick Wysocki</title><subtitle>Rick Wysocki is an Assistant Teaching Professor and holds a PhD in Rhetoric and Composition, focusing on the relationships between archival research and material rhetoric. This site includes his academic portfolio and his blog.</subtitle><author><name>Rick Wysocki</name></author><entry><title type="html">Notes on the Design of This Site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web/2019/10/07/design-notes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notes on the Design of This Site" /><published>2019-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web/2019/10/07/design-notes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web/2019/10/07/design-notes.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;switching-up&quot;&gt;Switching Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a hobbyist developer / programmer. A byproduct of this is that I don’t typically have a “real” web project to work on, so I end up designing and redesigning my own website to try out new techniques, frameworks, and libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m ending this annoying practice. &lt;!--more--&gt;It doesn’t promote actual writing (the apparent purpose of a blog) and just ends up a confusing mess of content strewn across multiple sites and folders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I’ve decided to commit to a simple but functional site design: more or less what you’re seeing now. I may make minor changes as I notice problems, but ultimately I’m attempting to shift my focus to writing. Hopefully, this will force me to finally start some more interesting digital projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-notes&quot;&gt;Design Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to use this post to collect information regarding my site design, in case others’ want to reference it for their own projects. Due to work contraints, this will probably roll out over a few phases, starting here with a basic list of the tools and technologies I used in this site design. It’s a living document, and I’ll timestamp revisions as I add them. If you want further explanation of something, feel free to mention it in the comment box below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools-and-technologies&quot;&gt;Tools and Technologies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the follow tools and technologies in the design of this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;: Jekyll is a Ruby-based static blog generator. I love it. Everything is neat and tidy, and I get to write in Markdown. Jekyll gets deployed to Github Pages (see below).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matejlatin/Gutenberg/wiki&quot;&gt;Gutenberg Typography&lt;/a&gt;: I’m lazy and hate setting up typography for sites, so I used Gutenberg. Because the Grunt-based compiling wasn’t reliably working for me (definitely user-error: I didn’t know what I was doing), I just scraped all their good CSS out into a new, static CSS file after a successful compile. It looks great though–many thanks to the Gutenberg folks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;SCSS&lt;/a&gt;: After I scraped out all of that compiled CSS, I wanted to make it more manageable for site-wide updates. So I reformatted the page as a dynamic SCSS stylesheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/inukshuk/jekyll-scholar&quot;&gt;Jekyll Scholar&lt;/a&gt;: It’s doing all the citation. Works great besides a few very minor quirks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;: The repository that I push my site to. Not that much to it, except that Jekyll-Scholar won’t compile on Github Pages. So I’m building my site with…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;: All my site building is handled with Netlify, which pulls from my Github repository. This makes Jekyll Scholar functional, as well as any other Jekyll plugins I add&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Rick Wysocki</name></author><category term="Web" /><summary type="html">Switching Up I’m a hobbyist developer / programmer. A byproduct of this is that I don’t typically have a “real” web project to work on, so I end up designing and redesigning my own website to try out new techniques, frameworks, and libraries. I’m ending this annoying practice.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Political Parties (But Not the Kind You’re Thinking)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/politics/2019/09/28/on-political-parties.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Political Parties (But Not the Kind You're Thinking)" /><published>2019-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/politics/2019/09/28/on-political-parties</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/politics/2019/09/28/on-political-parties.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/trump-art.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pop art images of  Donald Trump&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump is a fascist. &lt;!--more--&gt; He activates the latent microfascisms of everyday life in the United States, gradually transforming them into open state fascism. I have no qualms about impeachment. But I do question the ways that centrist-liberals frame impeachment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider #impeachmentparty. As with many viral phenomena, it is difficult to trace the hashtag’s point of emergence, but the among the more prominent examples I saw was Ava Duvernay’s, which read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are dressed and ready for the #ImpeachmentParty. What are you wearing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We are dressed and ready for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ImpeachmentParty?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#ImpeachmentParty&lt;/a&gt;. What are you wearing? &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Svwqw3RWAh&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Svwqw3RWAh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ava DuVernay (@ava) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ava/status/1176631308237197313?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The text was accompanied by an image of Duvernay, and others, in celebrity-carpet regalia. DuVernay poins to the camera as though her finger might somehow rewind political regression. The tweet garnered over eighty-three thousand likes, ten-thousand retweets, and eighteen-hundren replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These numbers were unfortunately insufficient in their  attempt to will Trump from office. The mechanisms of the US government need a greater level of engagement to work properly. This tweet is symptomatic of a discourse so tied to the “spectacle” that it seemingly just forgets rather obvious points related to history, cause and effect, and political strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guy Debord theorized the “society of the spectacle” as the seamless integration of social representation, society, and capital. Politics, in this society, becomes a &lt;em&gt;spectacle&lt;/em&gt; to be  passively viewed at a distance, rather than a grounded practice to be engaged democratically. In “The State of Spectacle,” Debord writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We have seen the falsification getting thicker, descending to the fabrication of the most trivial things, like a sticky fog which accumulates at the ground level of daily life. We have seen a striving for the absolute–as far as “telematic” madness–in the technical and police control of men and natural forces, a control whose errors grow as fast as its methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first target of this analysis should be politicians, technocrats, and certain media establishments who have reduced politics to symbols and representations. The advertising-based Internet model incentivizes engagement over ethics, leading these representations to transform according to the whims of corporations and their ability to  mobilize digital campaigns while dissuading a coherent political subjectivity. As Natasha Lennard has powerfully written in her excellent book &lt;em&gt;Being Numerous&lt;/em&gt;, “We participate in the social order. . . but we have not yet (for now) chosen to be collective, or communized or united” (118).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The society of the spectacle existed before Trump. A figure like Trump could gain political power only in a society already primed for the spectacle. This point is made in Adam Curtis’s postmodern documentary &lt;em&gt;Hypernormalisation&lt;/em&gt;. (I will leave it to readers to draw their own conclusions about Curtis’s postmodern documentary style.) Trump has radically accelerated the spectacularization of political life, and that he is a uniquely and globally dangerous figure. If you have made it this far, you already know that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visual rhetoric performed by Duvernay’s image further sediments a representation of political power as something given rather than collectively built. #impeachmentparty unhelpfully aestheticizes resistance to Trump. Precarious viewers might read Duvernay’s the image as a return to normalcy for an elite rather than as a pointing to a truly progressive future. I worry that this representation and others like it may dissaude unactivated, non-Trump voters from showing out at the polls. (An important first step against beating fascism, of course, is beating Trump.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Headlines referring to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-7501249/Rosie-ODonnell-Ava-Duvernay-Hollywood-elites-celebrating-Pelosis-impeachment-inquiry.html&quot;&gt;“Hollywood Elites”&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teenvogue.com/story/juiciest-donald-trump-impeachment-memes-nancy-pelosi&quot;&gt;“juciest memes”&lt;/a&gt;, in my view, reify a distanced, acontextual view of what impeachment means. Throwing this into focus was the fact that, within days, Nancy Pelosi had  begun attempts to narrow the impeachement inquiries focus to Trump’s dealings with Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no mandate that attending to representation must be regressive. Walter Benjamin famously claimed that while fascism aestheticizes politics, communism responds by politicizing art. From this perspective, there are ways that the representations made available to us through artistic expression can function to move forward positive and progressive political aims. Furthermore, as Natalie Wynn wonderfully argued, abandoning aesthetics leaves often makes the Left seem quite uncool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, all vectors of the left-of-center would do well to avoid an aesthetic that reinscribes a normalcy of power relations. Rather, an inclusive aesthetic should seek to grow the progressive base. Given concentration camps on our southern border, the continuation and re-emeregence of regressive social policy, and a rapidly deteriorating planet, it is not yet time to party.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rick Wysocki</name></author><category term="politics" /><summary type="html">Donald Trump is a fascist.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/trump-art.jpg" /></entry></feed>